First of all, put the plate buckle as a custom button to be added.
Select the button at the window of the object, then find the plus sign next to the shape, click the plus sign to enter the custom button interface.
We first modify the name to plate buckle, then open the button OBJ, and select the grid.
According to the ratio, the corresponding width and thickness are set, and the axis conversion has been pre-adjusted here, so we do not need to set it specifically.
Regarding the custom button, we also made a video to explain, and you can watch this video step by step.
Then let's make a pattern of the buckle head side.
Make a width of 45 mm and a height of 1 mm, select this plate, and use the other half of the inner column of the column layer.
Put the particles of these two plates together.
Change the width of the column to 5, change the thickness of the collision to 1, and change the thickness of the curve to 2.
Then put the plate buckle over the 3D window, freeze the top plate, and then naturally simulate the bottom plate.
After the simulation is complete, the whole is frozen.
Copy the plate on the other side.
Use the edit tool to select the leftmost side and pull it to the left.
When pulling, right-click, you can edit the distance of movement.
Enter 10 mm.
We can use a fixed needle.
Select the front end of the back of the plate, and select the position where the key shape ring is.
It is recommended to add two fixed needles on the ring separately.
Next, we move the sewing line to the position of about half.
Select the plate.
First, remove the frozen hole.
Then use the positioning ball to pull in the direction of the X-axis to the middle, so that there is a reunion part in the middle.
Then move towards us.
After completing this operation, simulate.
Pull two fixed needles, add a round plate with a diameter of 15 mm.
Change the particle diameter of the plate to 5, and change the thickness of the collision to 1.
Add a sticky layer to it.
The type of choice of the bottom ring cannot be stretched.
Adjust to the position close to the ring.
Then use the free sewing tool to sew the plate and round plate.
At this time, you can switch to the texture surface.
You can be more clear.
According to the 3D window.
Sensitive sewing.
After sewing, simulate.
Then delete the fixed needle.
Make it more natural to simulate.
Here you can see.
There is a little bit unnatural at the opening.
We can set the folding angle here to 270 degrees.
Make it perpendicular to the round plate.
This place is a little unstable.
We can turn off the folding of this place in the attribute editor.
If it still doesn't work, you can turn it off.
If it's still unstable, we can delete the sewing line.
Re-monitor the stability and sew again.
At this time, you can see that it is relatively stable.
Then turn to the back view.
Use a fake sewing needle to fix the round plate and the other side of the plate.
Do the sewing.
When we fix it.
You need to pay attention to the position of the fixing.
Because the plate of the plate is facing us.
So pay attention.
The fixed position should be the edge of the plate.
And not close to the position of the center of the plate.
Adjust the position of the fake sewing needle.
Combine the angle to determine its position.
After adjustment.
Delete the fixed needle of the ring part.
And combine the effect of simulation.
Adjust the position of the fixed needle at the end of the hinge.
Next, add the buckle of the plate buckle to the round plate.
Select the buckle.
In the property editor, turn off the conflict.
Adjust the size of the round plate.
Here we can double-click the center point after selecting the round plate.
When the top of the outer frame becomes orange.
You can use the center point as the reference point.
Quickly adjust the size of the plate.
Finally, adjust the suture of the buckle.
Make the plate buckle look more natural.
Next, apply transparent fabric to this round plate.
Select the round plate.
Apply a new default fabric.
Reduce the opacity to the lowest.
At this time, this round plate is transparent.
Delete all fixed needles.
Remove the cold hole on the other side of the buckle.
We store it as a clothing document.
Convenient to use next time.
Next, we add the plate buckle to our clothing.
Click to add clothing.
Add the plate buckle document.
Then, in the 2D window,
Put the plate buckle to the blank.
In the 3D window,
Add a place near the place to add.
The demonstration here is
Face our left side as a buckle.
Right side as a buckle.
You can see that the face has been pre-set.
The position of the sewing.
The internal line here will be slightly longer than the buckle.
The extra length is convenient for us.
Adjust the buckle to both sides.
To straighten the buckle.
You can add one more.
After you tighten one internal line,
Set another internal line according to your needs.
As a reference,
Here are two internal lines.
The diameter is 2 mm.
Next, put the plate buckle on the sewing.
Before sewing,
We can take the clothing rendering type.
Change to the texture surface.
We use a free sewing tool.
When sewing,
You can follow the high blue dots in 3D window.
To identify the position of the sewing.
First, set the starting point.
Click when you set the end point.
You can set the length of the sewing line in the window
On the left side, we set the length of the sewing line to 25 mm
Set 28 mm on the right side
Switch to the edge sewing line tool
Then we switch the view to the bottom
Convenient for us to adjust the sewing line
Keep the seam allowance and the seam allowance of the neckline even
This can prevent a pull in the corresponding position
After adjustment, simulate
Here you can see the seam allowance has some hammering effect
You can add a stitch to the seam allowance
Here, choose the hardest bottom collar, no seam allowance
At this time, you can see that the seam allowance on the side of the buckle is a little unbalanced
Make adjustments
After adjustment
Copy another plate buckle
The same operation, sew it to the opening position
Next, we apply fabric to the seam allowance board
Here, directly select the window of the lining
The seam allowance fabric is applied
Then modify the material type
Make it more shiny
And change to a uniform color
Use the color stripper to directly absorb the color of the body
Apply
Here you can add the color from the color stripper
Add to the color board
Here we can copy the PBR sticker of the seam allowance fabric
Locking path
Next, apply PBR sticker to the OBJ app for fastening
And modify the material
Can be pasted on the previous path in the next step
and apply the corresponding PBR sticker directly to the same path.
You can see that the plate buckle made of real silk fabric has a certain sense of gloss.
Then this plate buckle effect is finished.